Yuto Takamoto

Software Engineer

An engineer with industry experience in web and cloud technologies, CICD pipelines, and systems administration and automation. I have a healthy interest in new and exciting technologies, a love for teaching others, and a drive for making an impact wherever I go.

yuto@takamo.to

2016753392

Fairfax, VA



yuto.takamo.to

linkedin.com/in/ytakamoto

github.com/remiscarlet

TECHNOLOGIES





LANGUAGES

Python









PHP









Javascript/Typescript









































WORK EXPERIENCE

Sr. Software Engineer Etsy Inc.

10/2019 - 04/2021

Brooklyn, NY

Responsibilities/Accomplishments

- Helped set long-term architecture goals and design decisions as the team grew from three to seven engineers.
- Gracefully took ownership of a critical financial auditing system and aspects of its business processes when the original sole maintainer unexpectedly left the company. This system audited all financial records that were rolled up into publicly reported figures, processing tens of terabytes of data per day.
- Contributed a significant amount of work documenting, refactoring, and automating aforementioned system due to its previously poorly maintained state. Once stabilized, I also conducted long-term knowledge transfer and cross-training sessions to reduce SPoF risk.

Software Engineer Etsy Inc.

06/2017 - 10/2019

Brooklyn, NY

Responsibilities/Accomplishments

- Worked on the Compliance Engineering team to engineer and maintain systems and tools to enforce SOX Compliance.
- Trained and mentored a junior engineer from a non-programming background by building a lightweight curriculum and spending a significant time both on and off hours to help get them up to speed.
- Developed a slew of new internal tools, dashboards, and web interfaces to automate manually performed analyst tasks.
- Built an automated heuristics-based commit flagging algorithm and its associated infrastructure to flag potentially financially material code to be scrutinized under extra business processes.
- □ Further, also developed an integrated webapp survey system for the above tool to replace a multi-thousand line excel spreadsheet that was manually generated and emailed to engineers en masse. Survey system accounted for complex compliance requirements in flow and usage cases, and was regularly updated with new features as per analyst requests.

PERSONAL PROJECTS/VOLUNTEER WORK

Yukkuricraft, Founder (11/2012 - Present)

 Online gaming community hosted using a combination of AWS, GCP, and a self-hosted server to manage various server, networking, data storage, and monitoring needs. Responsibilities include community management and relations, and working with a small team of engineers on internal tools, features, and infrastructure.

Japan Center of New Jersey, Systems Administrator (06/2015 - Present)

Volunteer administration and management of LEMP stack with Django on Amazon technologies to manage local Japanese community center's online infrastructure by creating and managing mail, membership, class, web and payment systems.

Amat.su/kaze (12/2015 - Present)

A themed url shortener website built using Py/Django, Docker, GCP, and full CICD automation with Github. Includes Chrome and Firefox extensions.

EDUCATION

School of Computer Science Carnegie Mellon University

2013 - 2017